<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MarkelCA.com</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MarkelCA.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A collection of my open source projects and personal experiments. Most of these focus on developer tools, systems programming, and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-clapinvim&#34;&gt;⚡ &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markelca/clapi.nvim&#34;&gt;clapi.nvim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language:&lt;/strong&gt; Lua&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Frameworks:&lt;/strong&gt; telescope.nvim&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neovim plugin to display and navigate the public interface of your modules. Makes it easier to understand and work with large codebases by showing you what&amp;rsquo;s exposed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34; &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;./img/clapi.gif&#34;  alt=&#34;Second image&#34;  class=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tunadb&#34;&gt;🐟&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markelca/TunaDB&#34;&gt;TunaDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language:&lt;/strong&gt; Rust&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Frameworks:&lt;/strong&gt; clap, tokio&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A disk-based key-value store implementation. Built to learn Rust and explore storage engine fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/profilepic.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;Profile Picture&#34;  class=&#34;profile-image&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer based in San Sebastián (Spain), passionate about backend systems, AI, and developer tooling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the last 5 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked primarily in backend engineering, focusing on REST APIs, event-driven systems, and AI-driven automation. I&amp;rsquo;ve built optimization algorithms for a booking allocation engine, large-scale serverless data pipelines, an enterprise-grade AI-powered automation platform, and modular, highly testable API backends.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m especially interested in distributed systems, high-performance applications, and tools that improve developer productivity. Lately, I’ve enjoyed experimenting with AI coding agents, guiding and supervising them through well-defined implementation plans to speed up delivery while keeping quality high.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conquest of the Useless</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-10-17-conquest-of-the-useless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-10-17-conquest-of-the-useless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Has anyone ever told you that? They’ve told me more than once, I told that myself too, and I’ve been wrong every single time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;./img/maths.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Math equations&#34;  class=&#34;center&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can understand the fact that we need to focus on our objectives, that we need fixed career paths (although we already know they might change), just to keep moving and not to get paralized due to the vast knowledge that we’re missing along the way. We have to stick to it because otherwise we might get lost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trade-Offs on Monolith vs. Distributed Architectures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-09-13-trade-offs-on-monolith-vs-distributed-architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-09-13-trade-offs-on-monolith-vs-distributed-architectures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days there is much talking about distributed architectures and event-sourcing models, especially in cloud infrastructures and Kubernetes clusters. It has gained a lot of momentum in the last few years, and it may look for some people that is the ultimate solution for their architecture coupling and scalability problems. I’ve been reading about it in the last weeks, and I thought about sharing my considerations on it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering breaking your monolith into microservices, this article may be for you. I’ll try to dissect the trade-offs and defend the monolithic approach for some situations under certain practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
